Guide to the John Lakin Brasher Papers, 1857-1993 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Material Series, 1883-1973 and undated
  - Serials Subseries, 1910-1971.
    - The Christian Witness and Advocate of Bible Holiness, 1933, Jan.-1946, June 6 (Box 55)
    - God's Revivalist and Bible Advocate, 1941, Oct.-1969, Sept. (Box 55)
    - The Herald, 1953, Oct.-1971. Apr. (Box 55)
    - Hollow Rock Glad Tidings, 1937, Jan.-1967, Aug. (Box 55)
    - Journal of the Alabama Conference, 1916- 1938 (Box 56)
    - The Methodist Challenge, 1946-1955, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - The Way of Faith and Neglected Themes, 1915, June-1931, Dec., (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous Serials A-W, 1910-1971, (4 folders) (Box 57)
  - Pamphlets Subseries, 1883-1970 and undated
    Pamphlets, chiefly concerning religious topics. Pamphlets are divided into five categories (Biographical, Doctrinal, Methodist, Nazarene, and Miscellaneous) and arranged chronologically within each category.
    - Biographical, 1928-1970 and undated (Box 58)
    - Doctrinal, 1883-1961 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 58)
    - Methodist, 1910-1955, (3 folders) (Box 58)
    - Methodist, 1961-1967 and undated (Box 59)
    - Nazarene, 1905 (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, 1892-1965 and undated (Box 59)
  - Tracts Subseries, 1914-1969 and undated
    313 religious tracts concerning a wide variety of topics. Tracts are grouped according to author or publisher when a significant body of work by one author or publisher is represented in the collection. One envelope contains tracts on Pentecostal and Holiness topics. Most items are undated.
    - John L. Brasher and William Clifton Coe, 1945-1962 and undated, (12 tracts) (Box 60)
    - Peter Eldersveld, 1962-1969 and undated, (23 tracts) (Box 60)
    - Free Tract Society Publishers, undated, (26 tracts) (Box 60)
    - Herald Press, Publishers; Ebenezer Myers; and H. W. Patterson, Publishers, undated, (16 tracts) (Box 60)
    - Norman Vincent Peale, 1952-1959, (11 tracts) (Box 60)
    - Pilgrim Tract Society, Publishers and W.A. Swift, undated, (11 tracts) (Box 60)
    - W.M. Tidwell, undated, (19 tracts) (Box 60)
    - Pentecostal and Holiness Tracts, 1914-1933 and undated, (20 tracts) (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous Tracts, 1926-1967 and undated, (8 envelopes containing total of 175 tracts) (Box 60)
  - Hymnals Subseries, ca. 1910-1919 and undated (9 volumes)
    Bound shape-note and round note hymnals. Covers and pages missing from some items. Arranged chronologically.
    - Hymnal (Shape-note, title missing), John T. Benson Co., ca. 1910 (Box 61)
    - Tones for Jesus, 1911 (Shape-note, 2 copies) (Box 61)
    - Hymns of Glory, 1914 (Shape-note) (Box 61)
    - Praise Evangel, 1919 (Shape-note) (Box 61)
    - Hymnal (Round note, title missing), undated (Box 61)
    - Old Time Camp Meeting and Revival Songs, undated (Round note) (Box 61)
    - Spiritual Songs, undated (Round note, 2 copies) (Box 61)
  - Yearbooks Subseries, 1913-1948
    Yearbooks from Central Holiness University, John Fletcher College, and Cleveland Bible College. Arranged alphabetically by title, then chronologically.
    - Alethia (Central Holiness University), 1913-1924 (9 volumes) (Box 62)
    - Clebico (Cleveland Bible College), 1948, (1 volume) (Box 62)
    - Sylvis (John Fletcher College), 1925-1927 (3 volumes) (Box 62)
  - Clippings Subseries, 1895-1973 and undated, (4 folders)
    Clippings (with some photocopies) pertaining to Brasher and the organizations with which he was affiliated.
    - 1895-1973 and undated (Box 63)
  - Camp Meetings Subseries, 1909-1969 and undated
    Programs, invitations, promotional literature, and certificates from camp meetings. Arranged chronologically. Also includes a handwritten and typed history of Brasher Springs Camp Meeting by John Lakin Brasher.
    - 1909-1969 and undated (Box 63)
  - Promotional Literature Subseries, 1913-1969 and undated
    Literature advertising church services, institutions, organizations, and a variety of merchandise, both religious and secular. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1913-1969 and undated (Box 63)
  - Programs Subseries, 1909-1969 and undated
    Programs for commencements, performances, and ceremonies at church-affiliated schools; programs for Holiness and Methodist conferences and ceremonies; and church bulletins. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1909-1969 and undated (Box 63)
  - Reports and Newsletters Subseries, 1908-1968 and undated
    Conference reports; reports by churches and church agencies regarding projects or missions. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1908-1968 and undated (Box 73)
  - Railway Timetables Subseries, 1919-1931
    Six timetables from railways including the Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe; Southern Railway System; Missouri-Kansas-Texas Line; Delaware and Hudson; Rock Island; and Frisco. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1919-1931 (Box 73)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material Subseries, 1910-1969 and undated
    Postcards, maps, applications, instruction sheets. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1910-1969 and undated (Box 73)
- Transcriptions of Tape Recordings Series, 1950-1983.
  Transcriptions of tape recordings, chiefly of Brasher telling stories, delivering speeches, praying, and giving sermons. Includes transcripts of Bible lessons and taped letters by Brasher. Contains some transcripts of reminiscences of Brasher and speeches from the reception upon the donation of Brasher's papers to the Special Collections Department of Duke University. Pages are numbered, and an index to the transcript is included in box 63. A few pages are missing.
  - Index (Box 64)
  - Pages 1-55, (6 folders) (Box 64)
  - Pages 56-80, (3 folders) (Box 65)
- Financial Papers Series, 1855-1969 and undated
  Receipts and accounts for personal and church-related expenses; insurance policies; property assessment; financial reports for churches and religious organizations. Some photocopies. Arranged chronologically. A separate folder contains financial papers relating to Brasher Springs Camp Meeting, John H. Snead Seminary, and Central Holiness University. Includes 23 small ledger and account books for both personal and church related expenses.
  - 1855-1969 and undated (Box 66)
  - Brasher Springs Camp Meeting; John H. Snead Seminary; and Central Holiness University, 1906-1963 and undated (Box 66)
  - Volumes:
    - Grocery Book, 1954 (Box 66)
    - Personal Ledger 1923-1930 (Box 66)
    - A.L.S. Treasurer's Book, undated (Box 66)
    - Day, Memorandum, and Account Book, 1895- 1896 (Box 66)
    - Account Book of First Churches Served, undated (Box 66)
    - Farm and Food Expenses, Records, and Accounts, 1950-1966 (Box 66)
    - General Accounts, 1909-1918 (Box 66)
    - Ledger, 1929-1936 (Box 66)
    - Dormitory Account Book, 1910 (Box 66)
    - Conference Secretarial and Personal Accounts, 1920 (Box 66)
    - Conference Secretarial and Personal Accounts, 1921-1922 (Box 66)
    - Subscription Book for Remodeling and Completing John H. Snead Seminary, 1906-1907 (Box 66)
    - Book Orders, undated (Box 66)
    - Minutes Subscriptions, 1917- 1918 (Box 66)
    - Central Holiness University Book of Assets, Liabilities, and Expenses, 1917 (Box 66)
    - Subscriptions for H. C. Morrison Fund, 1905 and List of Likely Contributions to School Building, undated (Box 66)
    - Accounts Received from Various Sources for Conference, 1903-1905 (Box 66)
    - Benevolence Fund Subscription List, ca. 1902 (Box 66)
    - Personal Expenses, undated (Box 66)
    - Conference Givings List, 1905 (Box 66)
    - Conference Minutes Subscription List, 1904 (Box 66)
    - Personal Ledger, 1951-1964 (Box 66)
    - Personal Ledger, 1937-1950 (Box 66)
- Legal Papers Series, 1856-1963 and undated
  Documents granting power of attorney; indenture records; land records; record of postal appointment; contracts; records concerning the contribution of land to establish Brasher Springs Camp Meeting. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1856-1963 and undated (Box 66)
- Pictures Series, 1870-1983 (bulk 1900-1950).
  Chiefly copies of original photographs of John L. Brasher; his family; and Holiness preachers. Photographs of the staff and students of John F. Snead Seminary and Central Holiness University are included. Includes several photographs of camp meetings. Photocopies of photographs and a few pictures removed from printed works are included. Photographs are numbered and arranged in numeric order. List of photographs in box.
  - List of Photographs (Box 67)
  - Photographs, #1-131, (4 folders) (Box 67)
  - Printed Reproductions and Postcards (Box 67)
  - Photocopies (Box 67)
- Notebooks and Record Books Series, 1892-1902.
  Volumes containing membership rolls of churches and church organizations; salary and financial records; birth and baptismal records; funeral records; and personal memoranda. Some volumes concern churches where Brasher preached, while many are unidentified. A few notebooks kept by John L. Brasher's son Paul are included. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1892-1894, Wedowee, Ala. (Box 68)
  - 1897, Alton Park Station, Holston Conference (Box 68)
  - 1898-1899, Conference Board of Stewards and Children's Benevolence Fund (Box 68)
  - 1899, Simpson Memorial Methodist Episcopal Church (Box 68)
  - 1899-1900, Simpson Memorial Methodist Episcopal Church (Box 68)
  - 1901-1902, Simpson Memorial Methodist Episcopal Church (Box 68)
  - 1903, Saved and Sanctified, Clarkson, Mississippi (Box 68)
  - 1903-1906, Personal Notebook (Box 68)
  - 1905, People Saved or Sanctified in Boaz, AL (Box 68)
  - 1906, Parties who received minutes (Box 68)
  - 1907-1908, Bible Students, 1907-1908 (Box 68)
  - 1915-1916, Paul Brasher's Daily Memoranda (Box 68)
  - 1926 and undated, Stenographer's Notepads (Box 68)
  - 1943-1944, Bible School Attendance (Box 68)
  - undated, List of Bible Verses (Box 68)
  - undated, Paul Brasher's American Literature Notebook (Box 68)
  - undated, Personal Notebook (Box 68)
  - undated, Sanctification Record (Box 68)
  - undated, Some of the thoughts which come to me and people who may give money for seminary building (Box 68)
- Guest Books and Address Books Series, 1933-1957 and undated
  Six bound volumes, most unidentified, listing names and addresses. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1933, Address book (Box 69)
  - 1954, Hollow Rock Memory Book (Box 69)
  - 1957, Address and appointment book (Box 69)
  - undated, Address book (Box 69)
  - undated, Address book (Box 69)
  - undated, Funeral guestbook, unidentified (Box 69)
- Datebooks Series, 1906-1965
  53 pocket-sized datebooks in which Brasher recorded appointments, travels, and speaking engagements. Some entries record sermon texts. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1906-1965, (18 envelopes) (Box 70)
- Miscellaneous Series, 1910-1970 and undated
  Questionnaires, notes, lists of names, seating charts, receipts, commencement announcements, a short typed story from James Brasher's effects, subscription forms, etc. Most items undated.
  - 1910-1970 and undated, (4 folders, 1 envelope) (Box 71)
- Oversize Materials
  - Correspondence Series, 1905-1971 and undated (Box 72)
  - Methodist Episcopal Church, Alabama Conference Series: Church History Subseries (G) (Box 72)
  - Methodist Episcopal Church, Alabama Conference Series: District Statistics Subseries, 1931-1933 (Box 72)
  - Printed Material Series: Serials Subseries (Miscellaneous Serials, 1936-1960) (Box 72)
  - Printed Material Series: Tracts Subseries (Miscellaneous Tracts, 1940) (Box 72)
  - Printed Material Series: Clippings Subseries, 1933 (Box 72)
  - Printed Material Series: Camp Meetings Subseries, ca. 1910-1965 and undated (Box 72)
  - Printed Material Series: Promotional Literature Subseries, 1938-1968 and undated (Box 72)
  - Printed Material Series: Miscellaneous, 1936-1951 Financial Papers Series, 1917-1949 (Box 72)
  - Printed Material Series: Miscellaneous, 1917 and undated (Box 72)